Ayman Kastali

Software Engineer

Lives in: Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Phone: +971 555 952 741

Email: aymankastali1@gmail.com

Website: aymankastali

LinkedIn: ayman-kastali-python-developer

HEADLINE

• Certified Python developer by Meta with 4+ years of experience.

3+ years of volunteering work in tutoring coding.

Driven by passion and innovation, designed and created a Python web application (LinkedIn clone) includes lots of features like real time chatting, Social media authentication, Friendship requests, E-mail sender, And more.

Highly skilled in Python coding and scripting, Django framework, DRF, Data analysis, Machine learning, Deep learning, Web scraping and have excellent communication and team work skills.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Nationality: Syrian

Date of birth: 20, June 1994

EDUCATION

• Graduated from Faculty of Electrical and Electronical Engineering, Computer Engineering 2012 - 2021 University of Aleppo (Aleppo, Syria)

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Algorithms
- Programming languages
- Software and hardware skills
- Machine learning
- Deep Learning
- Database management system
- Networking

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Python Developer (Freelancing):

Feb 2019 - Present

Main Responsibilities:

- Design, develop, and implement web-based python applications using Django framework, APIs using DRF, GUIs apps using TKinter and ML models and classifiers.
- Tutoring Python for students who seek to learn Python and programming.
- Worked hands-on with a variety of data sources, project scenarios, and data analysis tools, including Excel, SQL, Relational Databases, Python, Jupyter Notebooks, and Cognos Analytics, applying data manipulation, data analysis, and data visualization.
- Creating many machine learning and deep learning models using supervised learning (linear regression, logistic regression, neural networks, decision trees), unsupervised learning (clustering, anomaly detection), recommender systems, and reinforcement learning.
- Applying the best practices and techniques for building machine learning models and challenging real-world problems.
- Creating extremely scalable, dependable, Python based software.
- Refactor existing applications to optimize its performance through setting the appropriate architecture and integrating the best practices and standards.
- Write clean, self-documenting code that follows best practices and design patterns.
- Participate in the entire application lifecycle mainly focusing on coding, debugging and testing.

 Ensure high quality code which is very well optimized utilizing the right design, algorithms and data structures.

IT Technician member in Technical support and Information security team at (Ihya'a Hallab al-Kadima): Mar 2022 - Sep 2022

Contract type: Full Time Main Responsibilities:

- Provide technical support (e-mail, phone calls, on-site support).
- Troubleshoot incidents, debug, and provide problem analysis.
- Configure & Maintain Routers, Switches & Firewalls/Policy Settings Etc.
- Configure & Maintain Server/Computer/Printer etc.
- Creating and managing Active Directory resources such as user AD Account, Groups etc.
- Design and deploy functional networks (LAN, WLAN, WAN).
- Monitor network performance and integrity.
- Responsible for the maintenance, configuration, and reliable operation of computer systems, network.
- Administrating Finger Print Access Control System. servers, and virtualization install and upgrade computer components and software, manage virtual servers, and integrate automation processes.
- Any other duties, which may be assigned from time to time by the Supervisor or Manager.
- Create mailbox, configure outlook web access, backup and restore mail.
- Configuring and administrating Windows based services DNS, DHCP.
- Configuration of firewall, creating restriction policies.
- Configure Monitor & Maintain the Routers, Switches & Firewalls.
- Installation and configuration of Print servers, Network Printers, share printer and assigning user rights to the printers.
- Software installations, network maintenance and Help desk support.
- Provide documentation and technical specifications to IT staff for planning and implementing new or upgrades of IT infrastructure.
- Supports the installation, configuration, and troubleshooting of hardware and software on PC workstations and laptops.

IT Technician member in Technical support team at (Arena Mall):

Jun 2021 - Mar 2022

Contract type: Full Time Main Responsibilities:

- Provide technical support (e-mail, phone calls, on-site support).
- Configure & Maintain Routers, Switches & Firewalls/Policy Settings Etc.
- Configure & Maintain Server/Computer/Printer etc.
- Creating and managing Active Directory resources such as user AD Account, Groups etc.
- Design and deploy functional networks (LAN, WLAN, WAN).
- Responsible for the maintenance, configuration, and reliable operation of computer systems, network.
- Administrating Finger Print Access Control System. servers, and virtualization install and upgrade computer components and software, manage virtual servers, and integrate automation processes.
- Troubleshoot incidents, debug, and provide problem analysis.
- Provide documentation and technical specifications to IT staff for planning and implementing new or upgrades of IT infrastructure.
- Any other duties, which may be assigned from time to time by the Supervisor or Manager.
- Create mailbox, configure outlook web access, backup and restore mail.
- Monitor network performance and integrity.
- Configuring and administrating Windows based services DNS, DHCP.
- Configuration of firewall, creating restriction policies.
- Configure Monitor & Maintain the Routers, Switches & Firewalls.
- Installation and configuration of Print servers, Network Printers, share printer and assigning user rights to the printers.
- Software installations, network maintenance and Help desk support.
- Supports the installation, configuration, and troubleshooting of hardware and software on PC workstations and laptops.

PROJECTS

- JobSearch (LinkedIn clone) web application :
 - Features:
 - Django allauth package for handling user authentication.
 - Django friendship package for handling friends requests, follows and blocks.
 - Beautiful GUI's using css grid system besides bootstrap.
 - Python decorators for security and managing pages access.
 - Email sender feature between companies and candidates.
 - Filter jobs by tag, city and job title for users who are looking for a job.
 - Super helpful page for HR to organize candidates, taking notes while interviewing and accept the best candidate.
 - Real time chat system.
- CRM (Customer relations management) web application.
- Live Notes web application using Django and React.
- Flowers delivery web application.
- Breast cancer detector using Deep Learning (CNN).
- Movies Recommender using unsupervised learning.
- E-Commerce web application using Django and JavaScript.
- Advertising agency web application.

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- Excellent at: Python Django framework Django Rest Framework TKinter Machine Learning Deep learning - Data analysis - Web scraping - SQL (PostgreSQL - MySQL - Oracle) - Git - HTML - CSS - IBM Cognos - Microsoft Power BI - Excel - Powerpoint
- Very good at: React JavaScript Java PHP(Laravel)
- Good at: C++ C# NoSQL (MongoDB)

SOFT SKILLS

- Critical thinking and collaboration.
- Communication, analytical, interpersonal, and leadership skills.
- Strong verbal and written communication skills Able to work on deadlines Time management.
- Passionate Team player Organized.
- Presenter and Public speaker.

LANGUAGES

- Arabic Mother Tongue
- English Fluent
- Russian Intermediate

CERTIFICATES

- Machine Learning Deeplearning.ai
- Supervised Machine Learning IBM
- Programming in Python Meta
- Programming with JavaScript Meta
- Data Analysis IBM
- Using Python to access Web Data Michigan University
- Python Data Structure Michigan University
- Using Python in AI Aleppo University
- Supervised, Unsupervised machine learning Aleppo University
- Building android apps with Java Aleppo University
- C++ Syrian Engineers Association
- CCNA New Horizons Institute

MEMBERSHIPS

• Syrian Engineers Association:

- Member as Computer Engineer

Jan 2022 - Present

VOLUNTARY ACTIVITIES

• Syria Trust for Development:

- Volunteer Apr 2016 - Oct 2019